Darryl Snow

Web professional with over 10 years of experience

Kunming, Yunnan, China (+86) 186-6911-7013 darryl@yourweb.expert https://yourweb.expert https://www.linkedin.com/in/darrylsnow

SUMMARY

I made my first website at age 13 and set up my own web design company at age 16. I have since worked directly on **Apple.com**, led the production team behind other large web projects for brands such as **Smirnoff.com**, **Baileys.com**, and **Lufthansa**. I have a strong and contemporary technical background matched with a keen eye for user experience, and a focus on accessibility, scalability, SEO, and performance. I've covered many roles in the web industry, so fit well into any team. I also have years of experience in building, managing, and training tech teams. Put simply, I work with such teams to make great products for the web.

EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed, Anywhere — Web Professional

1999 - PRESENT

- Impacted product scalability and usability through modern web design techniques
- Improved usability and performance by implementing cutting-edge JavaScript libraries like AngularJS
- Provided simple and reliable integration due to clear documentation and robust unit tests
- Shared knowledge and experience with junior developers, also improving workflow among distributed teams
- Proved myself a responsible and dependable remote worker

Mullen Lowe Profero, Beijing — Head of Research & Products

FEBRUARY 2013 - JULY 2014

- Introduced the team to new tools and technologies
- Sold new ideas to existing and potential clients through presentations and interactive prototypes
- Increased the value of the worldwide tech team through comprehensive training, example projects, and guidance materials
- Provided support to senior management via industry news and updates

Mullen Lowe Profero, Beijing — Studio Lead

JULY 2012 - FEBRUARY 2013

 Managed a team of ~30 designers and developers, overseeing the simultaneous production, launch, and maintenance of many

SKILLS

- Tech. team management
- Web project management
- Full-stack web development
- JavaScript (inc. AngularJS, ReactJS, Node JS)
- Advanced CSS
- DevOps / workflow tools
- Version control
- Responsive web design
- Teaching / training
- Hiring & interviewing
- Web performance optimisation
- Web accessibility
- SEO
- Web analytics
- QA testing
- Remote working
- Client / account management

ACHIEVEMENTS

I established my own company at age 16, designing and developing websites for local businesses. The success of this business funded my university degree.

Munch-5-a-Day was a fun and successful iOS application aimed at improving the health

Darryl Snow

Web professional with over 10 years of experience

Kunming, Yunnan, China (+86) 186-6911-7013 darryl@yourweb.expert https://yourweb.expert https://www.linkedin.com/in/darrylsnow

large-scale web projects

- Improved team workflow by implementing a pseudo-agile methodology and introducing practices such as kick-off, stand-up, and post-mortem meetings
- Improved team value by training them on and enforcing the usage of version control and unit testing
- Identified and rectified missing skillsets by hiring new talents

Mullen Lowe Profero, Beijing — Senior Account Manager

AUGUST 2011 - JULY 2012

- Successfully communicated requirements to the production team and status updates to clients
- Directly influenced major projects through feedback and advice, communicating clearly to clients technical ideas and constraints
- Increased the value of the account management team by creating templates and communication procedures
- Facilitated the production of websites and social media applications for major global brands including: Lufthansa, Diageo, Catalent, EA Games, Harper Collins, Village Roadshow, Lipton, Johnson & Johnson, Pizza Hut, Western Union, and MediaMarkt.

EDUCATION

Central St. Martin's College of Art & Design, London — *Graphic Design*

AUGUST 2005

A short summer course at one of the world's top art & design colleges to focus on typography, illustration, advertising, and photography.

University of Manchester, Manchester — B.Sc. Computer Science 2:1 (Hons)

2001 - 2004

My focus was on software engineering in Java and C++, with electives in functional programming, artificial intelligence, and network security.

consciousness of families and children. I designed, developed, marketed, released, and eventually sold it for a 6-figure US dollar amount. It was selected by Apple as App of the week throughout Europe for 2 weeks straight.

LANGUAGES

- English (native)
- Mandarin Chinese (fluent)

TRIVIA

- I have a full driving licence
- I once built and sold a craft brewery
- I was, for a time, a weatherman on national TV in China



Web professional with over 10 years of experience

Kunming, Yunnan, China (+86) 186-6911-7013 darryl@yourweb.expert https://yourweb.expert https://www.linkedin.com/in/darrylsnow

PROJECTS

Malts.com — Design & development lead

This is one of Diageo's larger websites, representing their entire range of Scotch whiskies. Working entirely remotely, I was the lead front-end designer and JavaScript engineer for this 10-month project, which was managed by a 3rd-party agency following SCRUM methodology. Based on detailed specifications, I set up the build system and developed an interactive, scalable, and modular design system, using a living style guide for client review. I also built all the JavaScript functionality, including an AngularJS application to help users search through and filter the range of products. All the code was fully tested and documented, and all project deadlines and KPIs were met.

Direct Asia Car Insurance Quote Generator — AngularJS app

Using Bootstrap and AngularJS, I worked fully independently to design, build, and test a fully responsive mobile web application. I was provided with a rule matrix and a RESTful API on which to create the application for users to be able to generate their own, rather complicated, insurance quotations quickly and easily on any device or platform. My test-covered code was seamlessly integrated by the company's in-house team and has provided an excellent return on their investment.

Apple.com (Chinese) — Localisation & front-end development

On several occasions I have been hired by Apple to work from their headquarters in Cupertino. I have localised existing pages in preparation for product launches, ensuring usability and performance, as well as created standalone mobile–friendly pages specifically for the China market. Following Apple's own strict design and copy guidelines and using their in–house code libraries and version control system, I completed the front–end development and was approved by Apple QA.

Smirnoff.com — Project management team leader

Working closely with a team of developers, as well as with distributed design, management, and client teams in London and New York, I oversaw the production of Diageo's flagship brand's website from design and development through to deployment and the establishment of an ongoing maintenance programme. It involved training the team to implement cutting edge SEO and performance techniques in order to meet both business and user needs.